Layton Avery

Software Developer Atlanta, Georgia

laytonavery5@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/laytonavery · https://github.com/LaytonAvery-https://github.com/LaytonAvery-https://github.com/LaytonAvery-https://github.com/LaytonAvery-https://github.com/LaytonAvery-https://github.com/laytonavery-https://gi

Project-focused software developer and coding bootcamp graduate. Specializes in utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Express, Node, and MongoDB to build mobile-responsive websites from scratch. Strengths include adaptability, exceptional communication, effective problem- solving, and time management. Extremely detail-oriented due to years of experience in healthcare.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Python, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap, MongoDB, MySQL

Education

- Software Engineering Immersive, DigitalCrafts—Feb 2021-May 2021
- BS Cardiorespiratory Science, *University of South Alabama*—Aug 2015-May 2017
- BA Biology, Troy University—Aug 2011-May 2015

Experience

Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2021-May 2021

• Developed multiple mobile-responsive web applications in software engineering training course covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript and Python, with an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node, Express, and MongoDB.

Respiratory Therapist

Jan 2016-Jan 2021

- Created patient care plans based on patient assessment with the goal of improving patients' quality of life; Provided patient education and teaching.
- Managed ventilator therapy; monitored and documented physiological responses to medications and therapy via EMR software such as EPIC, Cerner, and Allscripts Sunrise.

Current Projects

Pharmaci May 2021

• Designed application that generates fictional pharmaceutical names for medications at the click of a button. Built with Javascript, Node, Express, MySQL, React Bootstrap, and React.

DaintyDesignz May 2021

 Building an ecommerce site with user authentication, fully functional checkout process, and admin screens. Building with Javascript, React/Redux, Node, Express and MongoDB.